Mario Naia

Portfolio: https://marionaia.github.io/

Skype: live:marionaiaferreira

Email: marionaiaferreira@gmail.com

Telephone: 914240810

A passionate Fullstack developer with a strong interest in creating innovative applications. With a solid foundation in software engineering and experience working in agile teams. I bring a dedicated and collaborative approach to my work.



Work Experience

Developer GMV(Frontex) (March 2022 - October 2023)

Worked as a frontend developer, using React and Node, creating dashboards for the European Union project about border control. The project consisted in an application for the standardization of the process of deportation of the European Union. The border office would complete the checklist and send the information back to the Frontex servers.

- Technologies React, C#, Azure, SourceTree and Figma.
- Worked in a team with 8 people and we used Scrum methodology

Developer Infolabix (Datwyler) (September 2020 - February 2022)

Worked as a developer, using React and Node, creating dashboards for the shopfloor of several factories who were responsible for producing plastic materials. These interfaces are used by the engineers, in several factories, to monitor the production and scheduling of parts and components

- Technologies React, Angular, NodeJS, Azure and SAP.
- Worked in a team of 7 people and we used Scrum methodology.

Frontend/Mobile freelancer (contract) (August 2018 - June 2019)

Worked as a Frontend developer, using Java, in an international project for the civil construction industry.

- Technologies React Native and Android Native (mostly java).
- Worked alone on this project.

Software Engineer at FABAMAQ (January 2018 - July 2018)

Worked as full stack developer and developed games suited for the Cambodian market. My responsibilities were developing new features for games, re-skinning of old games for new markets and debugging.

- Technologies Javascript and C++.
- Worked in a team of 8 people. Our software runs on casino machines in Cambodia.

Software Engineer at INESC (March 2017- December 2017)

Worked as backend developer in the development and test of a Monte Carlo based system for Electric Networks in a consulting project for a major distribution network company in Portugal.

- Technologies Microsoft SQL Server, Python, JavaScript, Haskell and C++.
- Worked in a team of 5.

Analyst at Deloitte (Setember 2016 - February 2017)

Worked with Hadoop ecosystem (Hive, HBase, Impala, Sqoop), SQL Server, 5515 (SQL Server Integration Systems) and Java.

- Technologies Microsoft SQL Server, Hadoop ecosystem, Java and Javascript.
- Worked in a team of 7 persons for a insurance/banking project in a nordic country

Education

Masters in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Faculdade de Engenharia da Universidade do Porto (FEUP) (from September 2010 to September 2015)

- Major Automation
- Final grade of 14/20 or in the ECTS grading scale B (Good)

Knowledge

Programming languages - C/C++, PHP, CSS, SQL, HTML, Java, Python, LaTeX, JavaScript

Applications - Netbeans, QtCreator, PostgreSQL, MySQL,React/Angular, Android Studio,Visual Studio Code. Fluent in Speaking and Writing English - level CI (IELTS).

Other

Volunteer in Santa Casa da Misericordia during 2 years. Developed public relationship skills. Driving

license (B)